NICOLE MULDOWNEY

DATA ANALYST









PROFILE

Numbers and problem solving have been a part of my life for as long as I can remember. Whether it was in my undergraduate studies of mathematics or throughout my prior experience in accounting and finance, I find myself doing calculations in most things I do. I have an affinity for numbers, a passion for learning, and a strong desire to help others. I am excited to use data analytics and help organizations make decisions with their data.

SKILLS

- PYTHON
- SQL
- POWER BI
- **TABLEAU**
- ADVANCED EXCEL (PIVOT TABLES, VLOOKUPS)
- **GOOGLE SHEETS/DOCS/SLIDES**
- **POWERPOINT**
- JUYPTER NOTEBOOKS
- **GIT/GITHUB**
- **KANBAN BOARDS**
- **MAC OS**
- **ORACLE, QUICKBOOKS**
- **DATAFACTION/AGILLINK**

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

- TEDx NASHVILLE
- · Walk to the End Alzheimer's
- Girls on the Run 5K
- Country Music Association member
- Troubadour Society Member (Country Music Hall of Fame)
- Nashville Rock n Roll Hall of Fame
- Nashville Contributor Newspaper
- Nashville Food Project

EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Data Analytics Bootcamp, March 2020 - June 2020 Data Analytics Jumpstart, October 2019

BELMONT UNIVERSITY

BS, Mathematics; 2008 - 2012 Minor, Business Administration

- Dean's List 2008 2012
- NCAA Division I. Cross Country & Track. Atlantic Sun All-Conference Team

DATA ANALYTICS EXPERIENCE

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

DATA ANALYTICS | MARCH 2020 - JUNE 2020

- Learned how to apply statistical reasoning through training in tools such as Excel, Python, SQL, Tableau, and Power BI
- Used real data from local companies in a variety of problem domains, such as healthcare, government, and digital marketing
- Gained practical experience in the analytics workflow extracting, transforming, and loading data, as well as storytelling, building reports, and creating dashboards

PROJECTS

NYC MARATHON - CAPSTONE PROJECT

- Created an interactive Tableau dashboard on NYC marathon results over the last five years to explore how results changed over time, to analyze any trends in age group or gender, and to see if there is a correlation with weather and gdp per capita to race results
- Used Python for exploratory data analysis, data cleaning, and chart creation
- Tools Used: Webscraping, Python, Tableau, Excel, Google Slides

NASHVILLE BUILDING PERMITS - PROJECT

- Used Tableau to create multiple dashboards from the Nashville building permits data for permits that were entered and issued in a rolling 3 year time period
- Created maps and graphs showing areas in Nashville that are growing the most, the types of buildings that are being constructed in those areas, and costs associated with this growth

WORK EXPERIENCE

SENIOR ACCOUNTANT (CONTRACT ROLE)

VITALITY LIVING | JANUARY 2020 - MARCH 2020

- Ran reports and analysis through Excel to support finance team, as well as using pivot tables to analyze monthly accrual journal entries and recommended new policy to senior leadership
- Prepared financial statements, reconciled general ledger balance sheet accounts
- Worked with auditors to fulfill requests on 6 of the senior living communities
- Supported an accurate and timely month-end closing of company's financial records

SENIOR REVENUE ACCOUNTANT (CONTRACT ROLE)

- SESAC, INC. | NOVEMBER 2019 DECEMBER 2019

 Developed and ran reports in Oracle and Excel to collect data
- Provided analytics ensuring proper metrics
- Identified improvement areas in documentation and system processes and implemented new solutions
- Coordinated with Licensing to ensure revenue recognized in GAAP accordance
- Identified and researched payment discrepancies and made reconciling adjustments
- Established and maintained fiscal files and transaction document records

SENIOR STAFF ACCOUNTANT

WILES + TAYLOR & CO., PC | JANUARY 2014 - NOVEMBER 2019

- Analyzed and cleaned sales data for online merchandise store
- Interpreted data discrepancies completed special projects & data analysis
- Reviewed and analyzed financial statements, filed annual reports and 1099 forms
- Projected cash flow of 18 clients and entities, reconciled accounts, reviewed contracts
- Worked on a collaborative team and recommended strategies for efficiency
- Completed payroll audits and prepared budgeted versus actual expenses

ASSISTANT BUSINESS MANAGER/BOOKKEEPER

HABER CORPORATION | MAY 2012 - JANUARY 2014

- Managed and reconciled accounts and general ledger
- Handled cash management, processed accounts receivable and accounts payable
- Prepared tour billing, budgets, and commission statements
- Corresponded professionally with clients and managers
- Booked journal entries and payroll